Phong Nguyen | Senior Software Engineer

Having 19 years of experience, I have worked in a variety of roles on a wide range of projects. I am passionate about software architecture and have a particular interest in building web applications using modern JavaScript frameworks.

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam (+84) 773 008 452 phongnn@gmail.com https://phongnn.dev

Experience

Senior Software Engineer. Self-employed. Jun 2018 - Present

- Created a progressive web app (PWA) for personal productivity, using React, OnsenUI on frontend, Express on backend, and Firestore database.
- Created a website that provided programming courses in Vietnamese.
 Used Next.js, Ant Design on frontend, Express and Firestore on backend.
- Created programming courses: JavaScript, React, Redux, Express...

Delivery Manager / Architect at FPT Software Malaysia. Dec 2015 - May 2018

- Played a key role in establishing FPT as a preferred outsource vendor for Malaysia's largest mail and parcel delivery company. Completed three projects of good quality and within budget.
- Designed a payment switch and the integration parts of a large bill payment system for the client.

Senior Developer at Potentiate Sdn Bhd (Malaysia). Aug 2014 - Sep 2015 Potentiate was an Australian market research company where I maintained a Java desktop survey designer, troubleshot online surveys, and developed web apps for visualizing survey results.

Senior Developer at FPT Software Malaysia. Feb 2010 - May 2014 FPT is a global leader in software outsourcing with many clients in Malaysia.

- Designed and implemented ETL solutions for Malaysia's largest oil and gas company, including a data mart for retail customer loyalty with around 4 million cards and 250,000 daily transactions.
- Designed and implemented an ETL solution for a large commercial bank to generate reports on loan management for the Central Bank of Malaysia.

Programming Teacher at Aptech Vietnam. Sep 2008 - Jan 2010 Taught object-oriented programming, Java, SQL Server, XML...

Team Lead at FPT Software (Vietnam). Jun 2006 - Jul 2008 Led three different teams of six to ten members on a large project that migrated over 1,000 applications from Lotus Notes to Microsoft SharePoint for a multinational oil and gas company.

Skills

System Design

Clean architecture, design principles & patterns, domain-driven design, microservices

Languages & Runtimes

JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Cloudflare Workers

Frameworks & Libraries

React, Next.js, Remix, Express, Apollo Server

Databases

MySQL, MongoDB, Redis

Others

WebSocket, RabbitMQ, Jest, React Testing Library, Cypress, Docker

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (Information Technology)

Posts & Telecommunications Institute of Technology Hanoi (Vietnam), 1999-2003

Master of Science (Business Intelligence & Analytics) Universiti Teknologi Malaysia Kuala Lumpur, 2020-2021